Secure the village. Intelligence suggests that it will be lightly defended, but just beyond the village is an encampment where a large group of armor has been reported and which may be called up to reinforce the enemy troops in the village.  It is strongly recommended that you avoid engaging this armor in the streets of the village. The field encampment is a local strong point, but it appears that they haven't had the time to entrench themselves yet - we have to strike quickly and take their warehouse, which will greatly hinder their efforts in this region.