The enemy is pushing on to Leningrad.  To prepare the defense of the city we need to slow down the enemy offensive by smashing their advancing units.  According to intelligence, the enemy's 56th Motorised Corps have advanced too far ahead of the main forces and its flanks are not sufficiently covered.  This opens a good chance to suppress the enemy's frontal offensive.  Approach their rear with a deep flanking maneuver and then destroy their heavy artillery and reserves.  Your strike is extremely important, so we'll provide as much air support as possible.