Now is the time to crush the enemy by hitting them in the heart, at the capital. You'll be advancing through the center, to Zeelow Heights, from the bridgehead on the left bank of the Oder.  The enemy defenses in this section are particularly strong, but if we cut through them here we'll have a clear path into Berlin's suburbs.
Your mission is to break through the deep enemy defenses, capture any villages and enter the outskirts of Berlin.