To some extent the KV 1 appeared accidentally. In the late-thirties the military and the design bureaus concluded that the future lay in heavily armoured tanks.  France and Russia were the only countries that managed to create such vehicles before WWII began.  At the time many could not yet imagine such a monster without multiple firing points and accordingly were designing multiple-turret tanks.

Multiple turret tank designs clearly needed to be abandoned because they turned out to be too heavy to remain effective.  The military gradually reduced their requirements from 5 turrets to 2 and the designers created a two-turret tank with acceptable characteristics, but just in case, they also designed a one-turret back-up modification, smaller in size but with heavier armour.  This design was called the Klim Voroshilov, or KV.  Both tanks were put to the test during early action in Finland.  As a result, the clumsy two-turret SMK proved to be as much of a failure as the KV was a success.  It easily negotiated the Finnish fortifications, remaining invincible to any contemporary tank and anti-tank guns, regardless of the distance and direction of their fire.

This "back-up" design, despite its many drawbacks, became the most powerful tank in the world for two years.  The Germans got first-hand proof of this when they invaded Russia.  Most of the KV's lost were due to crew's lack of experience or insufficient supplies, but in capable hands even a single such tank could stop a whole enemy division or take out over 30 enemy tanks in the course of combat.

During the war, the KV's armour was reduced in order to decrease the weight and improve reliability, but the Germans were also improving their anti tank weaponry and the KV 1 lost it's main advantage - invincibility, and was replaced by the IS tank.  

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  76 mm/L 41.6 /Q 111
Armament secondary       -  3x7.62 mm/Q 4000
Weight                            -  47 t
Max Speed                      -  37 km/h
Engine power                  -  600 hp
Crew                              -  5
Armor min/max               -  32/130 mm