The Soviets have sent three IS-2 tanks against our positions. Their tracks have been damaged in our minefield (red track icon over tank) and the tanks cannot move. However, they can still fire, preventing our troops from reaching the bridge. The only way to eliminate these tanks is to fire from the sides or from behind as the IS-2's frontal armor is practically impenetrable.  Reinforcements consisting of Pz. IV tanks have arrived to help us with this objective. The tanks are located in a valley between two heights which will allow our tanks to fire on them without being seen.  (all heights work this way). Take advantage of this to get close to the IS-2 tanks without being noticed. The Pz IV is no match for the IS-2 in a frontal assualt, but if it attacks from a height, the enemy will not be able to return fire.