The Soviet reconnaissance plane is relaying targets back to their heavy artillery battery.  The battery's A-19 heavy cannons can reach our positions while remaining out of range. You need to call up fighter planes to eliminate the reconnaissance plane. 

To call up fighters, press the button for calling up air support located just to the right of the minimap. Select the appropriate aircraft type (fighters) and specify their area of operation with a right click. 
Fighters will fly around the area for some time automatically attacking any enemy aircraft they discover. Note that once you call in air support, the button will be grayed out for some time.  Once it is yellow again you can call in the same type, or other types of air support.  