There is another small wooden bridge to the east, but only your infantry can cross it.  This bridge is defended by a pillbox that can easily eliminate any infantry using the river crossing.

Sneak your scout across this bridge and past the Soviet defensive positions (purple arrow on the minimap), there is currently no need to attack here, so it's best for your scout to ignore them. You may want to save the game, <F5>, before attempting to cross the bridge. You can load it later by pressing <F8>.

Using the scout.  The scout is specially trained to perform covert operations behind enemy lines. You can use his sneaking ability which makes him practically invisible to the enemy even while moving (click the "formations" button and select the "sneak" function). Since the scout moves rather slowly in this mode, we do not recommend using it all the time. The scout's range of fire allows him to eliminate the enemy while remaining safe from return fire (to view range of fire, press <Alt+R>). To detect an enemy ambush from long range, use his binoculars (press the "binoculars" button). Try to detect enemy as early as possible and shoot from the maximum possible range.