In 1940 the US military decided that they needed a small passenger vehicle to fulfill a number of tasks including communications, reconnaissance, towing artillery and other loads and transporting commanders.  What they wanted was something between a motorcycle with a side- car and an automobile.  Although the army asked 135 different American automobile manufacturers to submit bids for the project, only three companies came close to fulfilling the specifications, Bantam, Willys-Overland and Ford.  Although Bantam's model was first chosen, after heavy testing Willys eventually won out, largely due to a more powerful engine.  In order to meet production Ford was eventually given a contact to manufacture the vehicle also, based on the Willy's design.  The Ford was named the GPW - many people incorrectly assume that the GP means General Purpose - in fact it meant Government, 80" wheelbase with the W designating that it was a Willy's design.  The GP however did spawn the famous "Jeep" name.  This new jeep was easy to manufacture, easy to maintain and had excellent off-road capabilities, and so met the army's specifications perfectly.  

The jeep literally became a legend.  Britain, Russia and other Allied countries received tens of thousands of these vehicles and it served on every front of the war.  The Axis powers didn't have such a versatile vehicle in service, which even led the Italians to offer twice as much money for a captured jeep than they did for a captured tank!

In all, almost 660,000 jeeps were manufactured during the war years.  It served as a model for many imitations and even direct copying after the war and many of its initial design elements are still being used today.

SPECIFICATION:

Speed         - 105 km/h
Power         -  60 hp
Weight        - 1100 kg