This cannon probably takes the record for longest time to go from prototype to mass-production.  It had the misfortune of being developed between WWI and WWII when the U.S. Congress was reluctant to issue large funds for rearming the military.  On the other hand, the developers had plenty of time to improve their designs at leisure.

The work on the new howitzer began in 1920, but the military didn't purchase it at the time.  It was modified again and in 1928 it was tested and approved by the military and marked as the M1 Howitzer with an M1 carriage.  In 1934 the howitzer has again modified to use standard ammunition and renamed the M2.  A year earlier, in 1933 work began on redesigning the carriage, but 3 years later 2 different carriages were still being worked on.  By 1940, after a long series of alterations, the M2 carriage was finally ready.  By this time WWII was already under way so mass production finally began on the M2 Howitzer with the M2A1 Carriage.  During the war both the barrel and the carriage were upgraded yet again, producing the M2A2 barrel and the M2A2 carriage.  Thanks to standardisation, any barrel could be mounted on any carriage, which provided a large variety of models and markings.

The howitzer proved itself quickly as it was light, compact and reliable, and in terms of ballistics, the German LeFH 18 was probably the only superior howitzer in the same class.  The M1A2 was the U.S. Army's main divisional cannon and it was used in Europe, Africa and the Pacific.  The Americans continued the work on standardizing different parts and they eventually mounted the barrel from the M5 76.2mm cannon on the howitzer's carriage, producing an anti-tank gun.  Although the gun was successful in its role, it turned out to be a bit heavy for an anti-tank weapon.

In 1942 the Americans mounted the howitzer on the M3 medium tank chassis creating the M7 Priest self-propelled artillery unit.  By the end of the war, over 8,500 howitzers had been manufactured.  

SPECIFICATION:

Caliber         -  105 mm
Rate of fire  -  6 shots/min
Range         -  11.3 km
Weight        -  2260 kg