The Soviet Union, seeing that the Western powers were already drawn into WWII, sought to improve its strategic position.  Leningrad, a large industrial center and home of the Baltic Fleet was considered to be vulnerable to shelling from Finnish territory.  The Soviet government offered the Finns to swap territories surrounding Leningrad for Soviet-held lands in Karelia.  The Finnish government refused, counting on support from the British, French and fellow Scandinavians coupled with the strength of their defensive fortifications known as “Mannerheims’s Line”.

In late 1939 the Soviets attacked, believing that Mannerheim’s Line was considerably weaker than the Finns supposed.  The line held and proved to be a powerful defense, combined with unusually low temperatures and the resolve of the Finnish soldiers.  The offensive failed with heavy Soviet losses.  

The Finnish success was not long-lived however, as the Allies did not go beyond supplying weapons and the Soviets brought in reinforcements.  After an intense artillery bombardment the Soviets managed to break through the Mannerheim Line and Finnish loses were so great that continuing the war was not an option.  The terms of the peace agreement were far worse for the Finns in comparison with the Soviet’s initial offer but strategic stability for the Soviets was achieved only after heavy losses on both sides. 