Infantry can effectively storm buildings. Use the <alt> key when issuing the order, so infantry will enter the building instead of attacking it. Note that when infantry is under fire, they crawl. You can switch infantry to the offensive formation, so they will run towards the target while ignoring enemy fire. When infantry must cover large distances on foot, switching to the marching formation will give a speed bonus.