May 1940.  Taking advantage of Allied inactivity the Germans have captured Poland, Denmark and Norway and were getting ready to invade France.  The German command allocated practically all the forces available to them, putting together 136 divisions with 3,300,000, 7,378 cannons, 2,580 tanks and 3,824 aircraft.  147 French, British, Belgian and Dutch divisions opposed them, comprised of 3,785,000, 14,544 cannons, 3,099 tanks and 3,791 aircraft.  The Allies planned to exhaust the enemy with a long drawn out battle, as they had heavy defensive fortifications as well as control of the sea for resupply.  The Allies positioned half of their troops on the fortified Maginot line along the French-German border while the other half was positioned on the Belgian border, since the Allies believed the Germans would try to bypass the Maginot line there.  In case of a German strike these troops were supposed to aid the Belgian Army and secure the crossings over the Meuse River.  From this position along the Belgian border the Allied troops were in position not only to protect the Maginot Line’s flank, but to threaten the Rurh industrial region as well.

As the Germans went on the offensive the Dutch and Belgians fought their best, but were unable to hold them up, meanwhile, the campaign's outcome was being decided further to the south as the main German force was pushing through the Ardennes.  They managed to cut right through the Allied defenses here also and push the Northern Allied Group all the way to the sea.  The bewildered Allied command couldn't organize successful counter-strikes, though some Allied formations acted very efficiently and managed to push the enemy back in places.  French troops were still fighting when the British Expeditionary Force received an order to retreat and evacuate.  As a result, many of the best French troops were trapped at Dunkirk and France soon found it necessary to capitulate.