Recognition Manual Screen Help

On the right side of the screen you will see that all equipment and vehicles are divided by type.  You can access the individual listings by selecting the panel with the heading that best describes the type of unit you are interested in, selecting it again will close the list.  Use the vertical scroll bar to the right to scroll through the listings.  The following types of arms and equipment are included:
Transport – unarmored trucks and vehicles 
Artillery – guns, howitzers, mortars and large-caliber machine-guns
Self-propelled Artillery – artillery and large guns mounted on self-propelled chassis
Armored Transport – armored cars, tanks, motorcycles
Aviation – Aircraft 
Trains – locomotives, gun platforms and cargo wagons.

The screen’s heading will show the unit name, the left side of the screen shows a short description, including the unit’s purpose, a historical reference and a comparison to its closest counterpart in any opposing army.  Under “Specification” you can find the unit’s technical characteristics.  On the right half of the screen will be an enlarged picture of the unit.