Settings Screen Help

The Settings Screen allows you to modify various in-game options.  On the right side of the screen are five buttons, You can click on any of these buttons to display and modify their parameters.

The parameters that are displayed on the right side of the screen can be changed by clicking on their text or number fields.
Gameplay:
Player Name: Name of the current player
Difficulty: Easy, Normal or Hard

Sound:
Music: Music volume
Effects: Sound effects volume

Video:
Brightness: Picture brightness 
Contrast: Picture contrast
Gamma: Monitor Gamma Correction Level
Resolution: Full list of supported monitor resolutions
Textures: Texture quality High, Low, Compressed; 

Multiplayer:
Flag Score Limit: Limit the number of points to reach for capturing flags
Game Speed: 
Kill Score Limit: Limit the number of points to reach for killing opponents
Player Limit: Maximum number of players
Player Name: Your name
Server Name: Name of server if you are creating a game
Server Password: Use to create a password protected game
Time to Capture Flag: Amount of time it takes to for flag to change hands
Time Limit: Limit the total game time

Blood:
Blood: Turn infantry blood effects on or off

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right:
Restore Default Parameters: Return all settings to game default
Save Settings
Discard Settings and Exit