Mission Screen Help

The Mission screen appears after you select a mission in the Chapter screen.  The Mission screen consists of several parts: a heading with the mission title, on the left is a listing of objectives with descriptions, and to the right is a map of the mission location with a description.

Objectives List
The left part of the screen displays a window with a list of objectives to complete for that mission.  Mission success depends on you fulfilling major objectives related to defeating enemy forces, capturing territory or advancing your forces.  These objectives can be completed in any order.  Press the panel with the objective title to read the objective description.  Press the panel again to hide the description.  If there are many objectives, use the vertical scroll bar to the right of the window.  Use valuable tips given in the descriptions to complete your objectives with minimal casualties and risk.

Location Map
At the top right of the screen is a Location Map. The map shows open and forested areas as well as rivers, roads and villages or cities.  Objectives are marked with small flags.  An objective’s flag will be marked on the map when it is chosen from the list on the left.  Neither your own nor enemy positions or fortified structures will be visible on this map, but by studying the map, you can get useful information before a mission starts.  For example, you can find areas suitable for setting up an ambush (road curves, closed forest tracts), or areas where you can discreetly move your forces to an objective.
Mission Description
A text window with the mission description is situated below the location map.  The text describes what is currently happening on this sector of the front, explains current objectives and may also contain information related to enemy forces, including weaponry and vulnerabilities.  

Interface Selectors in order from left to right: 
Back – Move back to Chapter screen
GO! – Start mission