Create Game Screen Help

List of all available multiplayer maps is displayed on the left. Map name column shows the name of the map. Type column displays what type of game this map is designed for, either sabotage or flag control. Column Players shows maximum number of players that can play on this map. Map size displays relative size of the map.

Scaled down picture of the map is displayed in the window on the right.

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right: 
Settings - shows multiplayer settings that are independent of the map selected
Create game with current settings  - accepts current settings and selected map and starts a new multiplayer game
Back to games list - returns to previous interface.