Multiplayer Settings Screen Help

The following multiplayer settings can be changed:
Flag Score Limit (seconds) - one flag score point per second is awarded for holding a flag
Game Speed - Very Slow, Slow, Normal, Fast, or Very Fast
Kill Score Limit - between 1 point for killing a soldier and 100 points for destroying a tank are awarded 
Time to Capture Flag (seconds) - time delay in seconds before flag status changes 
Time Limit (seconds) - game time limit in secon