Games: Internet Screen Help

All games are displayed in the middle portion of the screen. Game status is displayed in the left column followed by game name and map name. Players' column shows two numbers, first - how many players joined the game, second - how many slots are available on selected map. Ping column shows ping time to server in milliseconds. 

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right: 
Create new games - shows create new game interface that allows to select map, set parameters, and create a new multiplayer game
Join selected game - joins game that is currently selected in the middle portion of the screen
Return to previous screen - goes back to interface to select multiplayer service.