GameSpy Chat Screen Help

Chat Window with players' messages is located in the left middle portion of the screen. Messages can be typed in the Chat Edit Box that is located under Chat Window. Click somewhere in the Chat Edit Box and then start typing. Press Enter to send message. 

Player's List that shows all players currently logged into Blitzkrieg GameSpy is on the right. Player's state shows whether the player is in the chat, away from keyboard, in game list screen, in staging room, or in game. Relation to this player shows of the following icons: Neutral Relation, Friend, or Ignored. Players marked as Friend are placed in GameSpy buddy list. All messages from players marked as Ignored would not be displayed. The last Name column displays player's name.

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right: 
Info About Player - shows and allows changing relation to currently selected player
Toggle Away From Keyboard Status - allows switching Away From Keyboard Status on and off
Whisper to selected player - allows sending private messages to selected player that wouldn't be visible to other players
Back to games list - returns back to previous interface. 