Mission Statistics Screen Help

The Statistics Screen shows a list of statistical data in table format.  The screen title on the top shows the type of statistics being displayed.  When moving from the chapter screen, results starting from the beginning of the chapter are displayed on this screen Chapter Statistics. When a mission is completed the results of the mission are shown on this screen - Mission Statistics.  An identical screen is also used to display overall game results.

In a campaign, the table contains 2 lines – your results and your opponent’s results.  Column titles in the table are abbreviated; you can read a more detailed description by pointing your cursor at the column title.