Recognition Manual Screen Help

The Recognition Manual screen provides access to a listing of each country’s armaments and support vehicles, with the exception of some small arms.  You can access this screen by clicking on the “Recognition Manual” button.  You can view individual pages by selecting the book icon to the right of the unit picture within the Units List Screen, Depot Screen or Modernization Screen.

The large panel buttons on the left of the screen allow you to access unit information by category.  

All Arms – A complete listing of all equipment and vehicles used by all participating countries.
Allied Arms – Equipment and vehicles used by the western Allied Armies.  
German Arms – Equipment and vehicles used by Germany and the Axis Powers
Soviet Arms – Equipment and vehicles used by the Soviet Union, including those supplied by the Allies through the Lend-Lease Program.

On the right portion of the screen you will see that all equipment and vehicles have been further divided by type.  You can access the individual listings by selecting the panel with the heading that best describes the type of unit you are interested in, selecting it again will close the list.  Use the vertical scroll bar to the right to scroll through the listings.  The following types of arms and equipment are included:
Transport – unarmored trucks and vehicles
Artillery – guns, howitzers, mortars and large-caliber machine-guns
Self-propelled Artillery – artillery and large guns mounted on self-propelled carriages
Armored Transport – armored cars, tanks, motorcycles
Aviation – Aircraft 
Trains – locomotives, gun platforms and cargo wagons.

The screen’s heading will show the unit name, the left side of the screen will feature a short description, including the unit’s purpose, a historical reference and a comparison to its closest counterpart in any opposing army.  Under “Specification” you can find the unit’s technical characteristics.  On the right half of the screen will be an enlarged picture of the unit.