Units Screen Help

On the left side of the screen is a window with a list of your units divided into two catagories, artillery and armored vehicles.  You can scroll through the list using the scroll bar to the left of the window.
The book icon to the right of the unit name gives you access to the built-in Recognition Manual, where you can find tactical and technical characteristics on the unit, as well as its history and usage during WWII.