Unit Upgrades Screen Help

Unit Upgrades Screen lets your upgrade your regular units. On the left side of the screen is a window with a list of your units divided into two catagories, artillery and armored vehicles.  You can scroll through the list using the scroll bar to the left of the window.  New units are displayed on the right. You can replace the chosen unit marked with dark arrow to the left of the name by another unit of the same type or your can decline the upgrade. Any experience accumulated by an old unit will be passed on to the new one when upgraded.  The total quantity of your units remains the same.

The book icon to the right of a unit's name gives you access to the built-in Recognition Manual, where you can find tactical and technical characteristics of the weapon type, its history and usage during WWII.

Interface Selectors in order from left to right: 
Default – Use default upgrades 
Upgrade – move to Chapter Screen