Our troops are engaged in a decisive operation to liberate our Balkan brothers. The enemy has concentrated significant forces in your area and set up deep defensive positions.  Your mission is to suppress the enemy resistance to the northwest of Yassy, capture the villages deep behind enemy lines and destroy their reserve group of forces. Remember that the enemy is very strong, so try to find a weak spot in their defenses.