Our troops took positions and are ready for the assault on the Mannerheim line. If the operation is successful, the war with Finland will be as good as finished.  Since your attack is so important to the general success of the offensive, you have several units of advanced experimental equipment.
Your missions is to break through the enemy defenses, capture or destroy all pillbox or bunker fortifications and destroy the opposition's defense headquarters, which is located in one of the fortifications deep inside the Finnish defenses.