By the second half of the thirties the German Army's Pz. I and Pz. II tanks were becoming obsolete.  To replace them, the standard Pz. III and heavy Pz. IV tanks were being designed. The Pz. III was intended for deep breakthroughs and equipped with a turret gun and machine guns for use against light armoured vehicles and infantry.  The Pz. IV was designed to suppress heavy enemy defences and deal with pillboxes and anti-tank guns and was thus armed with a short 75mm gun firing powerful high-explosive shells.  This division of duties however, proved to be fatal and practice showed that all tanks should be able to deal with multiple types of battlefield situations.  Attempts to significantly increase the Pz. III firepower didn't yield serious results, due to the turret's small size, but the designers did manage to improve the Pz. IV's anti-tank efficiency by increasing its gun length.  The Pz. IV, costing little more than the Pz. III, became the standard German tank during WWII and was re-categorized as a medium-class tank.

The Pz. IV handled well and thanks to multiple hatches all assemblies were easily accessible.  The tank was also readily modified and its armor and weapons were repeatedly upgraded.  It proved to be one of the best tanks in the world for its category and only the Russian T-34 and certain modifications of the M4 Sherman could successfully oppose it.  The famous German military theoretician and tank commander Guderian even insisted that instead of starting production of new Panther tanks, the Pz. IV should be further improved.  The tank was so reliable and effective that the Germans used it throughout the entirety of WWII.  

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  75 mm/L 43 /Q 87
Armament secondary       -  2x7.62 mm/Q 3000
Weight                            -  23 t
Max Speed                      -  40 km/h
Engine power                  -  300 hp
Crew                              -  5
Armor min/max               -  10/74 mm