In 1939 Germany demanded the return of the city of Danzig and the Polish territories that separated Eastern Prussia from the German mainland.  Poland refused to negotiate and the Germans began preparing for war.

Germany gathered 62 divisions with 1,600,000 troops, 2,800 tanks, 6,000 guns, and 2,000 aircraft.  Poland countered with 39 divisions including 1,000,000 troops, 870 tanks, 4,300 guns, and 400 planes.  The Germans were not only superior in numbers but in the quality of their vehicles and equipment.

Despite the fact that the Poles did not have the resources to secure their lengthy border with Germany, The Polish command refused to withdraw their troops deeper into the country.  They were counting on the resolve of their soldiers to hold the border until England and France, their allies, could arrange an attack on Germany’s Western front.

The Germans, knowing that the Poles were overstretched, used their tank divisions to cut the Polish defences on September 1st, and made their way to Warsaw.  Many of the Polish formations were surrounded and either annihilated or taken prisoner.  Although Warsaw managed to hold on for some time longer, by September 16th the main Polish army had been smashed.  England and France did declare war on Germany, but did not begin any military offensives even though they outnumbered the German forces on the Western front by 5 to 1.  The Polish government evacuated to England and by October 5th Poland was completely in German hands.
This was the beginning of the Second World War.