This battle is the decisive effort which will allow us to crush the last enemy defenses and capture Moscow.  We are opposed by units of the Briansk front.
Your mission is to break through enemy defenses to the south of Briansk, capture the depots, and then capture the railway junction to the north to cut off all escape routes open to enemy troops.
According to intelligence, the enemy defenses are strongest opposite your left flank, closer to Briansk.  The opposition also has significant reserves.  Engaging the enemy from the sides or rear will increase your chances of success.