During their offensive from the Kharkov-Belgorod wedge, the enemy managed to break through our forward defence positions. According to the intelligence, the next strike will be in your sector. When we're sure of the enemy's intentions, we'll be able to send you some reinforcements.
Your mission is to hold on until the reinforcements arrive, then mount a counter-strike and destroy the crack enemy group in the south.