The enemy offensive on the capital of our Motherland is exhausting itself.  According to the decision made by the Supreme Command, your units will join the fighting on the southern flank.  The 2nd enemy tank group positioned at your front has already gone on the defensive.
Your mission is to cut through the enemy defenses in the southern direction, hit their reserves, then capture the railway station to the southwest near Stalinogorsk.  The proceed to the rear of the opposition's crack group and crush it, taking the village to the north.