A powerful heavily armored self-propelled artillery unit created on the basis of the IS-2. Designed as an anti-tank weapon, it could deal with any German tank. Larger ammunition allowance than the ISU-152, but less powerful high-explosive shells.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  122 mm/L 46.3 /Q 30
Weight                            -  46 t
Max Speed                      -  35 km/h
Engine power                  -  520 hp
Crew                              -  5
Armor min/max               -  32/162 mm