Infantry can storm buildings. Use the <alt> key when issuing the order, so that infantry will enter the building instead of attacking it. Note that when infantry is under fire, they crawl. You can also switch infantry to the offensive formation, so they will run towards the target while ignoring enemy fire. When infantry needs to cover a large distance on foot, switching to the marching formation will give them a speed bonus