You need to escort this supply convoy up to the front where some of our boys are stranded.  They've been holed up there for a while and they need these supplies badly.  The enemy is probably waiting for us, so keep your eyes open for ambushes.  Intel also says that there is an armor group out there hunting down expected reinforcements and HQ won't be able to lend us any air support, so watch your backs. 