A light armoured car. Designed for reconnaissance and patrol. Could deal only with enemy personnel and non-armored targets. Insufficient off-road handling, weak armor and weapons.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  7.62 mm/Q 1386
Weight                            -  2.3 t
Max Speed                      -  80 km/h
Engine power                  -  50 hp
Crew                              -  2
Armor min/max               -  10/10 mm