Our forces are advancing on all fronts.  The enemy is writhing in agony, making their last desperate attempts to change the course of events back to their favor.  They have managed to cut through our front in the Ardennes and, taking the offensive, are trying to press on.  You are the last obstacle in their way.  
Your mission is to hold the town, at all costs, until the reinforcements arrive.  Then counter-attack and destroy the enemy.
Note that initially, due to bad weather, you will not have any air support.  As soon as the weather clears, it will come in full force.
Our intelligence reports that the Germans are planning to use some new super-weapon.