Thanks to our sudden attack and the might of our forces, the Polish offensive is developing successfully.  The opposition, however, is trying to win time and put up some sort of resistance.  At your section the Poles are concentrating troops to set up defensive lines.
Your mission is to capture the crossing and, using your superiority in tanks, take the town to the north destroying the opposing Polish forces.
Intelligence reports that the bridge is mined, but you may try to neutralize the guards by sending in commando paratroopers, thus preventing the bridge from being blown, and making your mission easier.