In the mid-thirties Poland, like many other countries, bought 50 Vickers 6 Ton light tanks from England. It was a cheap and reliable tank, quite decent by that time's standards. However, the Poles were not satisfied with the engine. Using the British tank as a base, they designed a new one with a powerful diesel engine.  It became the first mass-produced diesel tank in the world. The appearance was altered so as to be unrecognisable from the British design and its speed and maneuverability were improved. It was renamed the 7TP and proved to be the most successful adaptation of the Vickers 6 Ton design.

7TP was the only Polish tank that could rival the newest German tanks. In terms of armour and firepower it was more or less equal to the German Pz. III, but it was slower.  All German tanks put out of action during the Polish campaign were hit by 7TP’s.  Though the tank's success was rather modest, it was the only success achieved by Polish armored forces.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  37 mm/L 45 /Q 80
Armament secondary     -  7.92 mm/Q 3960
Weight                           -  9.9 t
Max Speed                    -  32 km/h
Engine power                -  111 hp
Crew                              -  3
Armor min/max               -  6/40 mm