Use the scout to eliminate the anti-air gun crews ("FlaK38 105mm Heavy AA Gun"). Sneak to the designated point through the town, use caution when traversing the park area.
 
To switch the scout to the sneak mode press the "formations" button and then the "sneak" function. Use his binoculars (<X> key) to detect patrols on motorcycles. Make sure to keep your distance from enemy units, if they detect your scout, they'll make short work of him!  

Sometimes it helps to change the game speed when the scout is in sneak mode (<+> and <-> keys on the keypad).