When the heavy anti-air guns are disabled by the scout, use your high-level bombers to take-out enemy defensive positions and fire points. Try to knock out the enemy light anti-air guns ("FlaK30 20mm Light AA Gun") and self-propelled "Wirbelwinds". Light anti-air guns can attack low-flying targets such as ground attack planes. If you destroy these guns, your ground attack aviation will be available for action.