So far our offensive has been successful. However, the Russians are bringing in reserves from the inner areas of the country, trying to set up a new line of defenses. Intelligence reports that there are still weak spots along that line, particularly here near Daugavpils.
Your mission is to prevent the enemy from strenthening their defenses, find weak spots and cut through the enemy front. This will ensure the success of our future operations.  Try to keep the river crossings intact.
Our air forces have complete superiority, so you can count on their full support.