Soon after the Bf 109 fighter was adopted by the German Air Ministry, they released specifications for a second fighter in order to stay ahead of the Allied powers.  It was clear that the plane needed to be faster, better protected and better armed.  Focke-Wulf turned the design work over to Kurt Tank, a well-know aeronautics engineer who designed a new airframe around BMW's new double-row air-cooled engine.  For all the genius of the design itself, it was probably the choice of BMW to power the plane that led to its quick acceptance by the Air Ministry, as the Daimler-Benz and Jumo factories were already stretched to capacity.  The engine also held an advantage over water-cooled designs due to its ability to better withstand bullet damage. 

The first tests of the prototypes in 1939 showed both the advantages and disadvantages of the design and Focke-Wulf spent some time ironing the problems out when BMW changed their engine design, prompting another redesign of the FW-190.  The new BMW 801 engine combined with the new design proved to be successful, and despite some cases of engine overheating was put into production.  

The FW-190 was first flown in combat over the English Channel conducting small group raids at low altitude.  They quickly learned that the new British Spitfire Mk V was unable to intercept this highly maneuverable and fast new German fighter.  The German raids followed no fixed pattern and randomly hit fields, trains, cities and towns, prompting the British to put their Spitfires and Typhoons in the air on a constant basis in order to patrol the skies.  For 360 flights made by the Focke-Wulfs there were 52,000 patrol flights made by British aircraft, and even then they were unable to ensure reliable protection against the German raids.   

The FW-190 was also successful due to the wide variety of weapons that could be fitted to its airframe as well as other modifications that made it a truly multi-purpose plane.  The Focke-Wulf was used as a fighter, bomber, interceptor, attack and night fighter.  Its superior firepower allowed it to destroy practically any enemy aircraft with a half-second burst from its main guns.  This versatile plane was constantly modified and improved, and its usefulness kept it in production until the very end of the war in 1945. 

SPECIFICATION:

Speed                -  610 km/h
Armament           -  2x20 mm MG-151
Armament           -  2x13 mm MG-131