Our operations are developing quite successfully. Soon Africa will be clear of the enemy, but the opposition is trying to hold on and even counter-attack. Thanks to our flank maneuver you now hold a position behind the German Marette defense line. The enemy will try to destroy you.
Your mission is to fight off the enemy tanks which managed to break through. After that you must cut through the enemy defenses and capture the settlement in the north, thus cutting off the opposition's supply lines.