Early in the war the Soviets understood that victory would come only if they had reliable means of countering the German tanks.  This task remained important throughout the war and the infantry began by using self-propelled artillery, much as the German infantry used the StuG's for support.  This was an imperfect solution though as they were not initially designed to counter tanks, so the Soviets designed their first special purpose tank destroyer when they crossed a T-34 with an SU-122M, changing the 120mm howitzer out for an 85mm barrel designed for anti-aircraft duty.  The result was the SU-85, which came into service in 1943 and proved to be highly effective against almost all of the tanks that the Germans could field at the time.  The Germans were not standing still though either and soon their tanks were being fitted with thicker armor, calling for a new approach.  The SU-100 was the Soviet answer.  The same T-34 chassis was fitted with a 100mm cannon and given better protection, while the overall weight was only slightly increased, meaning that it was just as maneuverable as the SU-85.  

The SU-100 entered combat in 1944 and proved its worth quickly.  For a machine with such moderate weight, it was one of the most powerful and well-protected anti-tank self-propelled artillery units in the world.  Its effectiveness on the battlefield spoke for itself as the SU-100 could destroy practically any tank while remaining almost invulnerable due to its low silhouette and the thick frontal armor.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  100 mm/L 53.5 /Q 33
Weight                            -  31.6 t