Americans have always respected the concept of firepower and the work carried out by other countries with respect to jet-propelled weaponry did not go unnoticed.  The idea of using non-guided rockets allowed you to build a lightweight and versatile unit that covered large areas with salvo fire.  While the Russians designed a system with long range, and the Germans rocket launchers were very accurate, the Americans, as usual, concentrated on making it as practical as possible.  They designed an all-purpose launching tube and then designed a collection of rockets with different weight, range and firepower characteristics to be fired from those tubes.  

Initially the clusters of launching tubes were installed on landing craft, and then on airplanes, amphibious craft and tanks.  Unlike the Russians and the Germans, the Americans designed an all-purpose unit that didn't need adjustments for different vehicles or rocket types.  Where other countries used specially designed jet-propelled salvo systems, the Americans just mounted a cluster of guiding tubes of the appropriate weight on a Sherman or Jeep, and then showed the opposition how they understood the concept of firepower.  Out of all the modifications of the rocket launcher, they liked the T-34 Calliope, also known as the Goliath, mounted on an M4 Sherman tank the best.   The Sherman could carry as many as 60 tubes, and because of its short range the system was often vulnerable to enemy infantry fire, so the Sherman's armor came in quite handy for protection.  

SPECIFICATION:

Caliber         -  114 mm
Fire time      -  30 sec
Range         -  5.4 km
Rails            -  60