The enemy is charging Germany's borders so we're mounting a counter-strike in the general direction of Bastogne.  If our offensive is successful, we'll push the enemy into the sea, or at least stop their offensive.
Your mission is to eliminate all enemies, capture any depots along the way, and destroy their heavy artillery.
Note that the enemy will have superior numbers of men and equipment as well as full control of the skies.  You may count only on your own skills, the excellent quality of our equipment and the unflagging spirit of our soldiers!