We need you to push forward in your zone in order for us to continue our advance into enemy lines.  Up ahead of you is a bridge that must be seized and held.  The enemy will undoubtably strike back, and unfortunately, our intel can't pin down a likely direction for their counter attack.  Set up a defensive point on either side of the bridge and after repelling their attack, move forward and cut off their supplies by taking the warehouse.  