By the beginning of 1945, the Soviets had driven the German Army out of Poland, Hungary, and the Baltics, and they were now fighting inside Germany’s borders.  The Allies were also pushing from the west in an effort to meet up with the Soviets and end the war.  Even now the Germans refused to capitulate and began strengthening their defenses around Berlin, attempting to make it virtually impregnable.  The Soviets gathered together 1,000,000 troops, 10,400 cannons, 1,500 tanks, and 3,300 aircraft to storm Berlin.  A multi-pronged attack was planned with offensive strikes along the Oder and Neisse rivers, combined with a direct thrust up the center via the Zeelow Heights.  

The offensive began on April 16.  A powerful artillery barrage and anti-aircraft searchlights provided cover for the tanks that advanced on the lines with sirens howling.  They quickly broke through the German’s defensive lines only to realize, to their horror, that it was not the main defensive line, which in fact still lay ahead of their forces.  They immediately came under heavy close range fire from the main German defenses and suffered heavy losses.  But due to persistence and heavy firepower they somehow managed to continue.  The other prongs of the offensive were more successful and kept the Germans from reinforcing the center.  After four days of fierce fighting the defenses on Zeelow Heights were completely broken and the Soviets captured the city after fighting for it street by street.  

Storming Berlin eliminated Germany’s last large group of troops and forced it to capitulate, ending the war in Europe.