In the spring of 1943, the Soviets, having driven the German army out of Stalingrad and the Caucasus and lifting the siege of Leningrad, continued to press on into the Ukraine.  The Soviet Command was trying to reach the river Dnepr while harassing the Germans every step of the way, as they did not have the resources to build reliable defenses along the entire front.  
The German Command decided to strengthen its available troops with the most advanced heavy weaponry and mount a counter-strike in the Kharkov area.  The Soviet mobile groups suffered badly and had to halt their offensive.  The Germans, however, didn't have the forces to build on their success either.  This produced a lull on the front, while both sides prepared for a new battle.

The decision was made to break through the front lines by using massive numbers of their most advanced heavy weaponry, including Panthers, Tigers, and the self-propelled Ferdinand guns.  The Germans concentrated on Kursk where the front line extended in an arc that embraced the Red Army.  By placing two groups at the north and south ends of the arc they meant to meet up around Kursk, in effect encircling a large portion of the Soviet army.  The Soviets planned to defend their positions, exhaust the Germans, and mount a counter-strike.  

The German army gathered 900,000 troops, 10,000 cannons, 2,700 tanks, and 2,050 aircraft.  The Soviets countered with 1,336,000 troops, 19,100 cannons, 3,444 tanks, and 2,170 aircraft.  While the numbers favored the Soviets, the weaponry and armor that the Germans fielded were far more advanced.  

The Germans began their offensive in the summer of 1943.  Heavy fighting lasted nearly a week and the Germans managed to reach the main defensive line and even break through it in some places.  Near Prokhorovka, a small village, one of the most massive tank battles in history took place with both sides suffering huge losses.  After this battle the Germans did not have the strength to continue the offensive.  The Soviet Command had managed to keep their reserves intact and immediately mounted a counter-strike that met with overwhelming success, turning the tide in favor of the Soviets who were able to keep the strategic initiative until the end of the war.  

While the Battle of Kursk raged on the Allies were landing in the south of Italy.