In the thirties, an Italian General, Douhet, developed a doctrine in which heavy strategic bombers should play the main role in any military offensive.  They would be used to completely destroy the enemy’s military and industrial capabilities, after which the army could move in and simply occupy the enemy territory after it had been totally destroyed.  

Although General Douhet's theory didn't convince anyone in his own country, it did have an influence on the development of air forces in many others, and especially in America.  The Americans, who were largely invulnerable to air strikes on their own continent, considered strategic bombers to be the most important type of aircraft, with the primary targets being enemy cities and industrial centers.  With this strategy in mind, the U.S. began to produce heavy four-engine bombers and escort fighters more actively than any other aircraft types.

The B-17 Flying Fortress is widely considered the most famous American bomber, but it was the B-24 Liberator that carried the most bomb loads to Germany and Japan.  Designed by the Consolidated Company, the B-24 was fast, powerful, carried a huge bomb-load and was well armed.  Its main advantage over Boeing’s B-17 though, was its extended range.

All of the American strategic bombers were armed with several large-caliber machine-guns in order to protect themselves from enemy fighters, but even with these arms a single plane usually couldn’t fend off enemy interceptors.  To counter this the planes were put together into close groups where each aircraft was responsible for a particular sector.  These groups, sometimes numbering over a thousand planes, proved to be very difficult targets for enemy fighters, and they never managed to turn back any of the very large groups from their targets.  The carpet bombings by these air armadas wiped whole cities from the face of the earth, and as the war was drawing to an end, these bombing raids were one of the most important factors in ruining the war economies of Germany and Japan.  By war’s end over 18,000 B-24 Liberators had been produced, more than any other strategic bomber in the world.  

SPECIFICATION:

Speed                  -  483 km/h
Armament           -  10x12.7 mm Browning
Bombs                -  4000 kg