The German Operation: Typhoon had begun as they gathered their forces in the Center Group and prepared for the final decisive strike to take Moscow.  

The offensive brought the Germans right up to Moscow’s city limits where heavy field artillery could reach the capital.  Although the onslaught weakened, the situation remained critical and any German success could have lead to the fall of Moscow.  It was imperative to stop the German offensive and the Soviet command decided to concentrate arriving reserves on the German flank instead of the front line.  

When the counteroffensive began, the Soviet forces numbered 1,100,000 troops, 7,652 pieces of artillery, 774 tanks and 1,000 aircraft.  They were up against the Center group of armies with 1,708,000 troops, 13,500 artillery pieces, 1,170 tanks and 615 aircraft.  While the Germans had numerical superiority in their favor, they were not as strong as the figures may indicate.  During the offensive their forces had been stretched, with rear echelons lagging behind, many tanks were inoperable due to the lack of spare parts and repair facilities.  Some artillery was also well behind the front lines and there was a shortage of ammunition and fuel for transports.  Perhaps even more significant is that the Germans did not believe that the Russians were capable of any serious counter strike.  

The German offensive continued to attack Moscow’s defenses throughout the beginning days of winter but it became obvious that they were losing steam and their reserves were exhausted.  This signaled the start of the counteroffensive.  The timing was shared with other momentous events such as the bombing of Pearl Harbor and the British offensive in Africa.  The Soviets struck at the German right flank, then followed with crack troops concentrating on the left and center.  The German front was thrown into disarray and the Soviet Command decided to surround and destroy the Center Group of armies.  Encouraged by their success, and eager to keep the pressure on, they bypassed the areas where the Germans managed to set up defenses, and continued their rush forward managing to surround the Germans completely.  The German command, however, recovered from the first onslaught, and took advantage of the thinly spread Soviet lines with several strikes to the south and west.  This allowed the Center Group to break through the surrounding ring of Soviet troops.

Although the Soviets did not have enough forces to completely crush the Center group, they did succeed in pushing the Germans back to a safe distance from Moscow and permanently eliminated any threat of them capturing the capital for the remainder of the w