The Lockheed P-38 Lightning's unusual design stemmed from the need to develop a plane with high maximum speed, climb rate and long range, all of which could not be met with a single-engine design.  These specifications produced a double girder design with one engine at the tip of each girder.  The XP-33 prototype first flew on January 27, 1939, but crashed during one of its test flights.  They soon received an order, however, for 13 experimental YP-38 aircraft.  Once in production the P-38 was used by the U.S. army in both the European and Pacific theatres and is credited with many unforgettable victories, including the interception and destruction of the Mitsubishi G4M carrying Japanese Admiral Isoroku Yamamoto, 885 km (550 miles) away from the plane's base on Guadalcanal.
 
The reconnaissance version of the Lightning had photographic equipment installed in place of weapons.  It was believed that the plane's advanced flying abilities would enable it to outspeed and out-maneuver enemy fighters easily.  The Lightening probably photographed the whole territory of Western Europe several times over during the last years of the war.  Writer and painter Antoine de Saint-Exupery, pilot of the Free France Air Squadron, was killed while flying a Lightening by a FW-190D which appeared at the very end of the war and was one of the few German fighters capable of intercepting the Lightning.

SPECIFICATION:

Speed                  -  635 km/h