By autumn of 1941 the Germans occupied vast stretches of Russia, but their initial hopes that the country would fall were dashed, as Russian resistance grew stronger.  Lacking the resources to advance along the entire front, the Germans decided to concentrate on the central push towards Moscow, aiming to complete the campaign before the winter. 

The German Center Group had 1,800,000 troops, 14,000 cannons, 1,700 tanks, and 1,390 aircraft.  1,250,000 Russian troops, 7,600 cannons, 990 tanks, and 677 aircraft opposed them.
Large German tank formations managed to break through the Russian defenses.  Near Briansk and Viazma, Russia’s main forces were surrounded and destroyed, allowing the Germans to rush onwards to Moscow.  The offense was then slowed by small groups of battle-hardened Russian soldiers who miraculously maintained control of many strategic river-crossings and crossroads.  Autumnal rains then further bogged down the German offensive by making roads impassable for resupply, repairs, and artillery that were lagging behind.  Insufficient supplies, problems with repairs, and heavy losses reduced the efficiency of the German tank units and air force causing the German offensive to stop short of Moscow and allowing the Soviets to bring in sorely needed reinforcements.