In 1941 the Soviets began looking down the barrels of the German StuG III assault cannons that were providing infantry support.  They quickly realized that they would need to devise a similar weapon and began designing self-propelled cannons on their successful tank bases.  The T-70's chassis served as the base for the SU-76 and the T-34 was used to construct the SU-122, but the heavy KV-1 tank offered the best chance for manufacturing a truly massive gun platform.  

Two projects were started producing some rather unconventional results.  One design, the KV-6, had two 45 mm cannons and a third 76 mm cannon, another, the KV-7 was equipped with two 76 mm cannons that both fired on one target at the same time.  When Stalin saw these designs for the first time he was a bit surprised, commenting, "Why three cannons? We need just one, but a good one."  His reaction led to the demise of both projects.  

Work went ahead on the lighter KV-1S chassis and produced two more designs; the KV-12 and the KV-14, which were armed with a 203 mm cannon and a 152 mm cannon respectively.  By this time the advanced German Tiger tanks were appearing and The Soviets decided to pour all of their resources into the model that would more effectively destroy heavy tanks.  The KV-14 design won out by February, 1943 and was manufactured as the SU-152. 

The SU-152 debuted in the Battle for Kursk and immediately showed impressive results.  A regiment of twelve of these self-propelled units destroyed twelve Tigers and Elephants in three weeks of fighting, and this isn't counting other tanks and self-propelled artillery units.  The SU-152 was nicknamed the "Beast Killer" by the troops who could even take on enemy pillboxes when supported by it.  By the end of the war the Beast Killer was being gradually phased out when production started on the more compact and well armoured ISU-152.  
SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  152 mm/L 32.5 /Q 20
Armament secondary       -  7.62 mm/Q 2702
Weight                            -  45.5 t
Max Speed                      -  43 km/h
Engine power                  -  520 hp
Crew                              -  5
Armor min/max               -  21/132 mm