Taking advantage of our strategic retreat, the opposition pushed dangerously deep into our battle formations and captured Kharkov. The most advanced equipment sent to you for reinforcements has been cut off at its unloading point without crews or ammunition.  The enmy forces however, have become seriously overstreched, giving us a favorable chance to launch a counter-strike.
Your mission is to fight off the onslaught of the advancing enemy units.  After that you must rescue the new equipment sent to you, which is currently located at the railway station to the southeast. Destroy the defensive point at the rail junction to the southwest which was captured by the enemy and is now blocking the railway line.