The Mathilda is the only tank in the world that was named for a woman.  In 1936 the Vickers Company was asked to design an infantry tank that could be produced for less than 6,000 Pounds Sterling.  The result was rather slow with limited firepower, but it was endowed with thick armour.  The first version, the A11, had many shortcomings, including room for only two crew, a single machinegun and an awkward "gearbox" with only one gear that allowed it to cruise at 13 km/h (8 mph). Improvements were already underway as testing on the new tank began.  The tank had to be made more effective at countering enemy infantry, gun emplacements and other tanks.  The A12 or Mathilda II resulted with improvements including a two-pound anti-tank cannon, a three-man cast tower and two diesel engines.  The frontal armour was also increased.  

Only two of the A12 designs were ready at the beginning of the war, but by spring of 1940 an entire battalion was ready.  In France the A11 and A12's achieved good results, as the German anti-tank guns were ineffective against their thick armour.  The battle itself, however, was lost and the British left almost all of their equipment behind when they evacuated from the beach at Dunkirk, effectively leaving them without any Mathilda I's.  The A12 design after this event was referred to as just the Mathilda.

In North Africa, the German African Corp's tank and anti-tank cannons were also powerless against the "Thick-Skinned Lady", and the only effective German counter against the Mathilda was their 88mm anti-aircraft gun, of which Rommel had few.  The Germans soon added the Marder II Tank Destroyer that was equipped with a 76mm Soviet cannon, to their arsenal, which also proved effective against the Mathilda, but her superior armour was still an incredible advantage and she eventually earned the nickname "Queen of the Battlefield" by the British Tank men.  Mathilda undeniably bore all the weight of the heavy tank battles during the first period of the African campaign.

By 1942 Mathilda was obsolete.  Various modifications, flame-throwers, floodlights to light the battlefield, mine sweep-nets, bulldozers and bridge cranes -were used until 1945, making her the only British tank which served the whole duration of WWII.

SPECIFICATION:

Armament primary          -  40 mm/L 50 /Q 92
Armament secondary       -  7.92 mm/Q 3150
Weight                            -  27 t
Max Speed                      -  25 km/h
Engine power                  -  190 hp
Crew                              -  4
Armor min/max               -  19/104 mm