Mission Screen Help.

A list of objectives required to complete this mission is displayed on the left. Mission success depends fulfilling major objectives, for example, defeating enemy forces, capturing strategic locations, or defending some area.  These objectives can be completed in any order.  Press the panel with objective's title to read detailed description.  Press the panel again to hide the description.  If there are many objectives, use scroll bar to the right of the window to scroll down.  Pay attention to valuable tips given in descriptions to win with minimal casualties and risk.

Mission map is located in the right top corner of the screen. This map shows open and forested areas, rivers, roads, and buildings.  Objectives are marked with small arrows. When an objective is selected in the list of objectives on the left the corresponding arrow is circled on the map. Neither your own nor enemy positions are visible on this map, but you can prepare for the mission by studying this map.  For example, you can find road curves and closed forest tracts suitable for setting up an ambush, or areas where you can discreetly move your forces to an objective.

Mission description is located below the mission map. The text describes what is currently happening in this sector of the front, explains current objectives, and may also contain useful tips about enemy forces, weaponry, and vulnerabilities.  

Buttons at the bottom in order from left to right: 
Go to Mission – starts mission
Back to Chapter Screen – returns to chapter screen to select a different mission.