[DISABLED] List of Units Screen Help.

The left part of the screen shows a list of units under your command that consists of two parts – artillery and tanks. Press on Artillery label to expand this list and view artillery units or Tank label to view tanks. Scroll bar in the center can be used to scroll up and down and see units that didn't fit on the screen.

The following information is available for each unit:
Unit type
Commanding officer's rank and name
Front, side, rear, and top armor values
Weapon values for damage and penetration.

Button to the right of unit type allows accessing the built-in recognition manual. More detailed tactical and technical characteristics and historical information can be found there.